commerceonline.com 2009-01-05

# TD Bank – Privacy Policy

Strong protection for your information

### Protecting Your Privacy

Through our subsidiary bank and financial service companies, we provide a comprehensive line of banking, investment and insurance services. As a company, we are committed to protecting the confidentiality of personal information you provide to any of our subsidiary companies.1 At the same time, the information you provide can help us introduce you to other products and services that we offer to help you meet your financial goals.

### Information We Collect

The type of information we collect depends on the type of product or service you obtain from us. We may collect “nonpublic personal information” about you. “Nonpublic personal information” is information about you, which is not available from public sources, obtained in connection with providing you with a financial product or service. For example, nonpublic personal information include information regarding your account balance, payment history and deposit account activity. It also includes your Social Security Number, account number and other information associated with you in particular through one or more identifiers. We may collect this nonpublic personal information from the following sources:

  * Information we receive from you on applications or other forms you may complete and provide to us, such as your name, address, Social Security Number, date of birth, assets, income and, in the case of applications for insurance, health and medical information;
  * Information about your transactions with us, with members of our corporate family or others, such as your account balance, payment history, products and services used, credit card usage; and
  * Information such as your creditworthiness, payment history, and other information that we receive from outside companies or third parties, such as credit bureaus, that we require in order to provide the products or services you have requested.

In some cases, we may obtain “protected health information” about you. “Protected health information” is information provided by a third party such as an insurer, health plan, employer or health care provider that identifies you and relates to your health or health care, including payment for that care. Among other things, our insurance subsidiaries may obtain information regarding your medical condition if you apply for insurance coverage, and we may obtain information regarding medical treatment that you have received in the course of processing payments for that treatment.

### Information We Disclose

We share information with our affiliates2 about our experiences or transactions with you or your account in order to help you complete financial transactions or make you aware of services and products from which you may benefit. The personal information we collect and share with affiliates may include your name, address, Social Security Number, policy number, account number, telephone number, account balance, payment history and deposit account activity.

Except as permitted by law, we do not disclose nonpublic personal information that we have obtained from other sources to any of our affiliates.

Under certain circumstances, we disclose personal information about you to “nonaffiliated third parties” (i.e., third parties that are not our affiliates or part of our corporate family). For example, we disclose personal information about you to third parties to assist us in servicing your account, to government entities as required by law or regulation, or in response to subpoenas, and to credit bureaus. We will not disclose any nonpublic personal information about you to any other third parties, except as permitted by law.

We may disclose all of the information we collect as described above, except protected health information, to companies that perform marketing services for us, financial institutions with which we have joint marketing agreements, or companies with which we jointly offer products or services such as credit cards or credit insurance.

We will also provide nonpublic personal information to affiliates and other parties if you request us to do so or you give us your permission.

If you decide to close your account(s) or become an inactive customer, we will continue to adhere to the privacy policies and practices described in this notice.

### Medical Information

_This notice describes how medical information about you may be used and disclosed and how you can get access to this information. Please review it carefully._

We do not frequently hold protected health information, but, for example, we may receive protected health information from a health care provider to assist in processing payments to that provider. Or, our insurance subsidiaries may collect protected health information and provide it to an insurer to assist in processing an insurance claim, or if you enroll to be a participant in a health plan. We are required to maintain the privacy of protected health information in accordance with the law and this notice, and to provide you with notice (including a paper notice upon request) of our legal duties and practices with respect to such information. We do not share protected health information among our affiliates or with third parties except to process transactions or to provide services you have requested or initiated. We may use or disclose medical information, including protected health information, in connection with the payment or collection of health care costs or insurance premiums, or for purposes of insurance claim processing, enrollment or underwriting. We will not use or disclose your protected health information for any other purpose without your written authorization, which you may revoke, or as otherwise required or permitted by law.

You have the right to request restrictions on our use or disclosure of your protected health information, although we are not required to agree to a requested restriction. You have the right to request that we communicate your protected health information to you in a confidential manner. You have the right to inspect, copy and, if it is erroneous, amend your protected health information. And, you have the right to receive an accounting of disclosures of your protected health information, although that right does not apply to disclosures to you or for purposes of treatment, payment or health care operations.

You may make any complaint about our use or disclosure of protected health information directly to us, or to the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and you will not be retaliated against for filing a complaint. If you wish to complain to us, or if you have any questions, please contact us as follows:

_**TD Bank, Attention: Compliance Department,  
2059 Springdale Road, Cherry Hill, NJ 08003  
Tel: 888-751-9000**_

or

_**TD Banknorth, Attention: Privacy Officer/Risk Contingency Management,  
Management, P.O. Box 9540, Portland, ME 04112-9540  
Tel: 800-211-1979**_

### Our Security Procedures

Access to your personal and account information is restricted to those employees who need to know that information as part of their job, to service your account or to provide products and services to you. We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards that are reasonably designed to guard your nonpublic personal information.

### Accuracy of Customer Information

We recognize that the accuracy of your personal and account information is critical to you and, to that end, we follow procedures to reasonably ensure the accuracy of your information. If you find that any information we have on file or have reported to another party does not appear to be accurate, please write to us at:

_**TD Bank, Attention: Customer Service Center,  
P.O. Box 5400, Cherry Hill, NJ 08034-0211**_

or

_**TD Banknorth, Attention: Loan and Account Research,  
32 Chestnut St., Lewiston, ME 04240**_

Please include your account or policy number.

### Internet Banking Privacy

Safeguarding your personal information when interacting with us via the Internet is also extremely important. We apply the standards discussed above in caring for your personal information. When browsing our website, personal information, such as your e-mail address, is not collected. Some areas of our website require information, such as your e-mail address or your account number, to enable you to perform certain tasks (e.g., to review your accounts or correspond with us). In these cases, we collect the information necessary to interact with you.

If you visit us on the Internet, we may place a “cookie” on your browser that records the number of visits made to our various web pages; however, personal information is not collected. If you use our Online Banking or eBillPay programs, you may receive additional cookies which contain your unique identifier, allowing you to view and manage your accounts. These cookies may be linked to personally identifiable information.

E-mail sent within our online banking system is secure. The secure online transmission of information to us is only available from within your online banking account after you have established a secure connection using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption. You may also contact us by phone, postal mail or in person.

We preserve the content of your e-mail, your e-mail address and our response, so that we can more efficiently respond to any follow-up questions from you. We also retain this information to meet legal and regulatory requirements.

### Regular Internet E-mail is Not Secure

Please do not send confidential information such as Social Security Numbers or account numbers to us via regular e-mail. In instances where e-mail addresses are provided, they are provided for information inquiries of a non-sensitive and non-confidential nature. Since an Internet e-mail response back to you would not be secure, we will not include confidential information in an e-mail response.

### Protecting Children Online

In accordance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act, we will not knowingly collect, store, use or disclose personal information from children. We define children as persons under the age of 13.

We do not accept applications directly from children, knowingly collect, nor share, personal information about them; unless the information has been provided by an adult in connection with opening a deposit account for or with the child. We won’t send any unsolicited promotions to users who indicate they are less than 13 years of age unless the solicitation is in connection with an account opened by an adult.

This does not prevent parents from opening deposit accounts on behalf of their children. We will obtain parental consent prior to the creation of an account on behalf of a child.

### Questions

We’re strongly committed to our relationship with you and want to be sure you understand the steps we have taken to protect your personal information. If you have any questions or comments, please call us at the appropriate number listed at the end of this document.

### The Problem of Identity Theft

Identity theft is a growing crime in our country. Each day, thousands of people become victims of identity theft. Identity theft occurs when someone steals your personal information and uses it to establish credit, charge items, or borrow money using your name.

### Protect Your Identity

  * Shred unused credit offers and other documents containing personal or financial information before discarding them.
  * Guard your Social Security Number.
  * Don’t release information to people you do not know, especially over the phone or Internet.
  * Review bank statements for accuracy.
  * If you are denied credit for no apparent reason, obtain a copy of your credit report.

### If You Become a Victim

  * Contact your bank and all others with whom you have a financial relationship.
  * File a police report if you have had a loss.
  * Report the fraud to the major credit bureaus: 
    * Equifax 800-525-6285
    * Experian 888-397-3742
    * Trans Union 800-680-7289

For additional help, call the Federal Trade Commission at 1-877-ID-THEFT or visit their website at: [www.ftc.gov/idtheft/](http://www.ftc.gov/idtheft/).

More information can be found at [http://www.TDBank.com](http://www.tdbank.com/) and [tdbanknorth.com](http://tdbanknorth.com/).

### It’s Your Choice

Federal law gives you the right to limit some, but not all, marketing from our affiliates. Federal law also requires us to give you this notice to tell you about your choice to limit marketing from our affiliates.

You may limit our affiliates2 — which include, but are not limited to, banking, leasing, insurance, wealth management, securities brokerage and investment advisory affiliates — from marketing their products or services to you based on personal information that we may collect about you and share with them. This information includes your account history with us. Your choice to limit marketing offers from our affiliates will apply until you tell us to change your choice. You can opt back in at any time.

To limit affiliate marketing offers, contact us either by:

  * Phone: **888-937-1050**
  * Web: [http://www.TDBank.com/opt](http://www.tdbank.com/opt)
  * Mail:  Complete and return the Opt-Out form provided in your Privacy Statement.  To obtain a copy, please visit any TD Bank location or call 1-888-751-9000.

**If you have previously informed us of your preference, you do not need to do so again.**

_Note: Your preference will be processed within 30 days of receipt and will remain in place until you change your option. Please note your preference may not prevent you from being solicited with information that the affiliate had on file prior to the processing of your preference. Your selection(s) will be applied to your entire household so, if you opt-out, no one in your residence will receive notifications of special discounts, offers and promotions that are available._

This privacy statement applies to the following entities within the TD Banknorth Inc. family, including TD Bank USA, N.A., TD Bank, N.A. and its divisions and subsidiaries listed below.

### TD Bank USA, N.A.

###  TD Bank, N.A. Divisions

  * TD Bank
  * TD Banknorth
  * TD Banknorth Mortgage
  * TD Banknorth Wealth Management Group
  * TD Banknorth Project Finance
  * TD Retail Card Services
  * Shoppers Charge Accounts Co.

### TD Bank, N.A. Subsidiaries

  * Bancnorth Investment Planning Group, Inc. 
  * Bancnorth Investment & Insurance Agency, Inc.
  * TD Wealth Management 
  * TD Equipment Finance, Inc. 
  * TD Bank Brokerage Insurance Services, Inc. 
  * TD Banknorth Leasing Corporation 
  * TD Insurance Agency (in New York) 
  * TD Equipment Finance, Inc.
  * TD Aviation Finance, LLC
  * TD Insurance, Inc.

1 A list of our divisions and subsidiaries is noted above.

2 Our affiliates include those companies that control, are controlled by or are under common control with TD Banknorth Inc. or The Toronto-Dominion Bank, including TD AMERITRADE, Inc., among others.

This privacy statement applies to individuals and not to business entities or business transactions. It is effective upon publication. We reserve the right to make changes to this statement. A current version of this statement will be issued at least annually and can be requested at any time. This statement is for general guidance and does not constitute a contract, nor does it modify or amend any agreements we have with you.
